Register of the Sir Karl Raimund Popper Papers, 1928-1995
Hoover Institution Archives
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1920s-1983
  - 3 prints depicting Karl Popper and wife Hennie at Alpbach, Austria, at his 80th birthday celebration., undated (Folder P)
    Includes Hans Albert, William W. Bartley, III, Herta Firnberg, Otto Molden, Stephen Kresge, Junichi Aomi, Gerd and Ingeborg Fleischmann.
  - 1 print depicting Karl Popper with Konrad Lorenz, possibly in Altenberg, Austria., February 21, 1983 (Folder Q)
  - 7 prints depicting Karl Popper and others at the Workshop on Open Questions on Quantum Physics, Bari, Italy., May 4-7, 1983 (Folder R)
  - 1 print depicting Karl Popper addressing the audience at the Karl-Popper-Symposium, Old City Hall, Vienna, Austria., May 25, 1983. (Folder S)
  - 1 print depicting Karl Popper with wife Hennie and Prince von Thurn und Taxis at Duino, Italy., September 20, 1983 (Folder T)
  - 1 print depicting Karl Popper at Alpbach opening ceremonies, Alpbach, Austria., August 1984 (Folder U)
  - 23 prints depicting Karl Popper (+6 dupl.), undated (Folder mV)
  - 1 print depicting Karl Popper with Peter Medawar, undated (Folder mW)
  - 12 prints depicting Karl Popper with Ingrid Belke and unidentified man., undated (Folder X)
  - 4 prints depicting Hennie Popper., undated (Folder Y)
  - 6 prints depicting the Poppers' home, including 1 print depicting Karl Popper working in his study., undated (Folder Z)
  - 26 prints depicting various people, including Joseph and Judith Agassi, Ingrid Belke, Josef Bohmer Renee Bouveresse, Horst Fissenewert, Adriaan D. de Groot, Fritz P. Hellin, Hilde Hoefert, Peter L. Krohn, Robert Lammer, Physer Leung, Raphael C. Pollock, David K. Probst, Elfrieda Sandicz-Jeilg(?), Sophie Schnabel Temple. Ernst Topitsch (with Gerard Radnitzky), and John R. Wettersten., undated (Folder mAA)
    Includes 1 print depicting participants to a conference at Cerisy-la-Salle, France, possibly July 1-11, 1981; 3 prints of panelists at an unidentified conference; and 1 print of a portrait of Ernst Gombrich.
  - 57 strips of negatives and 5 contact sheets of prints depicting Karl Popper and others., undated (Folder BB)
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS, 1928-1995 (Box 464-583)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS II, 1933-1998 (Box 464-511)
  Articles, conference papers, drafts of books, essays, lectures, speeches, and related correspondence, arranged chronologically by title
  - Unidentified writings, n.d.
    - General (Folder 464: 1-2)
    - Fragments (Folder 464: 3-4)
  - Address on philosophy, n.d. (Folder 464: 5)
    Typescript
  - "The Aimlessness of the Personalist Interpretation of the Probability Calculus,", n.d. (Folder 464: 6)
    Holograph
  - "Bell's Theorem: A Note on Locality,", n.d. (Folder 464: 7)
  - "Bell, Clauser, and Horne on Locality: A Criticism," (Folder 464: 8)
  - "Counterexamples to a Proof of Clauser and Horne" (with Thomas D. Angelidis) (Folder 464: 9)
    Holograph and typescript
  - "Critical Remarks on the Knowledge of Lower and Higher Organisms, the So-Called Sensory Motor Systems," speech (Folder 464: 10)
  - "Europe Now Exists,", n.d. (Folder 464: 11)
  - "Exorcizing the Observer from Quantum Theory,", n.d. (Folder 464: 12)
  - "How the Scientist Works,", n.d. (Folder 465: 1)
  - "The Left Side of the Clauser and Horne Inequality" (with Thomas D. Angelidis) (Folder 465: 2)
  - "Locality,", n.d. (Folder 465: 3)
  - "Logic, Probability, Deductive Dependence" (with David Miller) (Folder 465: 4)
  - "Marx's 'Capitalism' Never Existed,", n.d. (Folder 465: 5)
  - "A Note on Natural Laws and So-Called 'Contrary to Fact Conditionals'," (Folder 465: 6)
  - "On a Conjecture by Garrett Birkhoff and John von Neumann," (Folder 465: 7)
  - "On the Logic of Induction," (Folder 465: 8)
  - "On Probabilistic Independence," (Folder 465: 9)
  - Paper for conference on terrorism, n.d. (Folder 465: 10)
  - "Philosophy of Science: A Personal Report,", n.d. (Folder 465: 11)
    Holograph and typescript. Incomplete
  - "Prediction and Prophecy," (Folder 465: 12-13)
    Projected volume consisting of "Prediction and Prophecy in the Social Sciences," "The Poverty of Historicism," "The Nature of Philosophical Problems and their Roots in Science," "Towards a Rational Theory of Tradition," "What is Dialectic?" "Utopia and Violence," "Indeterminism in Classical Physics." Typescript and proofs
  - "Probability,", n.d. (Box 466)
    - Holograph (Folder 466: 1)
    - Typescript (Folder 466: 2)
  - "The Problem of Body and Mind," (Folder 466: 3)
  - Proposal concerning post-war treatment of Germany, n.d. (Folder 466: 4)
  - "Sketch of Memorandum," (Folder 466: 5)
  - "Some Comments on Truth and the Growth of Knowledge," (Folder 466: 6)
  - "Some Remarks on Carnap's Probability Theory,", n.d. (Folder 466: 7)
  - "Some Thoughts Concerning the Doctrine of Natural Selection,", n.d. (Folder 466: 8)
  - Speech on Goethe, n.d. (Folder 466: 9)
  - Speech on philosophical pluralism, n.d. (Folder 466: 10)
  - Speech on rationalism, n.d. (Folder 466: 11)
  - Speech on science in the universities, n.d. (Folder 466: 12)
  - Speech on The Open Society and Its Enemies (Folder 466: 13)
  - Transcript of discussion following lecture, n.d. (Folder 466: 14)
    See also Speech relating to fundamental ideas of The Open Society and Its Enemies (box 27, folder 7).
  - Transcript of interviews, n.d. (Folder 466: 15)
  - Untitled manuscript on indeterminism (Folder 467: 1-4)
  - "Ein Kriterium des empirischen Charakters theoretischer Systeme," Erkenntnis,., 1932-1933 (Folder 468: 1)
    English version. Holograph and typescript
  - Logik der Forschung, - English version, 1934 1959
    - Notes and calculations (Folder 468: 2)
    - Preface. (Folder 468: 3)
    - Introduction. (Folder 468: 4)
    - Chapter 3
      - Holograph (Folder 468: 5)
      - Typescript (Folder 469: 1)
    - Chapter 6 (incomplete)
      - Holograph with typewritten revisions (Folder 469: 2-4)
      - Typescript (Folder 469: 5)
    - Chapter 8 (incomplete). (Folder 469: 6)
  - "Atomic Clocks, Scientific Practice, and Logic," letter to Nature (unpublished),., 1940 (Folder 469: 7)
    Typescript and correspondence
  - "Interpretation of Nebular Red Shifts," letter to Nature,., 1940 (Folder 469: 8)
    Typescript, printed copy, and correspondence
  - The Open Society and Its Enemies, 1945 (Folder 470: 1)
    - English version
      - Unidentified edition, - Proofs (previously identified as first edition, ), n.d. 1945
      - Second edition, 1950 (Box 471)
        - Draft (incomplete).
          - Volume 1 (Folder 471: 1)
          - Volume 2 (Folder 471: 2)
        - Proofs
          - Volume 1 (Folder 471: 3)
          - Volume 2 (Folder 471: 4-5)
          - Volume 2 (Contd.) (Folder 472: 1-3)
    - German version
      - First edition, 1957-1958
        - Preface. (Folder 472: 4)
          Typescript and holograph
        - Corrections. (Folder 472: 5)
        - Proofs (Folder 472: 6)
      - Sixth edition, 1986
        - Preface. (Folder 473: 1)
        - Addendum. (Folder 473: 2)
      - Seventh edition, 1992
        - Correspondence, 1992 (Folder 473: 3)
        - Corrections. (Folder 473: 4-5)
        - Proofs (Box 474)
          - Volume 1 (Folder 474: 1-4)
          - Volume 1 (Contd.) (Folder 475: 1)
          - Volume 2 (Folder 475: 2-4)
    - Polish version,., 1991 (Folder 476: 1)
      Typescript preface
    - Russian version, 1992
      - Correspondence (Folder 476: 2)
      - Preface entitled "A Letter to My Russian Readers." (Folder 476: 3)
    - Bulgarian version, 1993
      - Correspondence (Folder 476: 4)
      - "A New Preface for My Bulgarian Readers." (Folder 476: 5)
  - "Humanism and Reason," The Philosophical Quarterly,., 1952 (Folder 476: 6)
    Review of E. Grasi and T. von Uexkull, Von Ursprung und Grenzen der Geistwissenschaften und Naturwissenschaften, 1950. Notes, typescript, and proofs
  - "The Nature of Philosophical Problems and Their Roots in Science," The British Journal for the Philosophy of Science, 1952
    - Holograph and typescript draft (incomplete) (Folder 476: 7)
    - Proofs (Folder 476: 8)
  - "The Demarcation between Science and Metaphysics," in Paul Arthur Schilpp, ed., The Philosophy of Rudolf Carnap, 1955 (Box 477)
    - English version
      - Incomplete drafts
        - Holograph (Folder 477: 1-3)
        - Typescript (Folder 477: 4)
    - French version,., 1979 (Folder 477: 5)
      Correspondence and typescript
  - "A Note on Tarski's Definition on Truth," Mind,., 1955 (Folder 477: 6)
    Typescript and printed copy
  - "A Note on the Body-Mind Problem: Reply to Professor Wilfrid Sellars," Analysis,., 1955 (Folder 477: 7)
  - "Two Autonomous Axiom Systems for the Calculus of Possibilities," The British Journal for the Philosophy of Science,., 1955 (Folder 477: 8)
  - "Adequacy and Consistency: A Second Reply to Dr. Bar-Hillel," The British Journal for the Philosophy of Science,., 1956 (Folder 478: 1)
  - "The Aim of Science," Ratio,., 1957 (Folder 478: 2)
    Revised version, 1959. Typescript
  - The Poverty of Historicism,., 1957 (Folder 478: 3)
    Preface to Russian version, 1993. Correspondence, holograph, and typescript
  - "Philosophy and Physics: The Influence on Physics of Some Metaphysical Speculations on the Structure of Matter,"., 1958 September 12-18
    Paper, 12th International Congress of Philosophy, Venice, Italy (published in Atti del XII congresso internazionale di filosofia, 1958)
    - English version. (Folder 478: 4)
    - French version,., 1987 (Folder 478: 5)
      Printed copy
  - "Back to the Presocratics,"., 1958 October 13
    Speech, Aristotelian Society, London, England
    - Proofs (Folder 478: 6)
    - Printed copy (Folder 478: 7)
  - "Evolution and the Tree of Knowledge,"., 1961 October 30 (Folder 478: 8)
    The Herbert Spencer Lecture, Oxford, England. Typescript
  - Conjectures and Refutations, 1962
    - Italian version,., 1972 (Folder 478: 9)
      Preface to second edition, 1985. Correspondence and typescript
    - German version, 1994
      - Correspondence
        - Albert, Gretl, 1983-1986 (Folder 478: 10)
        - Beise, Julia, 1989 (Folder 478: 11)
        - Schiffer, Eva, 1993-1994 (Folder 478: 12)
        - Siebeck, Georg, 1988-1993 (Folder 478: 13)
      - Typescript
        - Introduction (Folder 478: 14)
        - Chapter 1 (Folder 479: 1)
        - Chapter 4 (Folder 479: 2)
        - Chapter 7 (Folder 479: 3)
        - Chapter 9 (Folder 479: 4)
        - Chapters 11-14 (Folder 479: 5)
        - Chapter 17 (Folder 479: 6)
        - Chapters 19-20 (Folder 479: 7)
        - Appendix and bibliography (Folder 479: 8)
      - Proofs (Box 480)
        - Introduction (Folder 480: 1)
        - Chapter 1 (Folder 480: 2-3)
        - Chapter 2 (Folder 480: 4)
        - Chapter 3 (Folder 480: 5)
        - Chapter 4 (Folder 480: 6)
        - Chapter 5 (Folder 481: 1-2)
        - Chapter 6 (Folder 481: 3)
        - Chapter 7 (Folder 481: 4)
        - Chapter 8 (Folder 481: 5)
        - Chapter 9 (Folder 481: 6)
        - Chapter 10 (Folder 481: 7)
        - Chapter 11 (Folder 482: 1-2)
        - Chapter 12 (Folder 482: 3)
        - Chapter 13 (Folder 482: 4)
        - Chapter 14 (Folder 482: 5)
        - Chapter 15 (Folder 482: 6)
        - Chapter 16 (Folder 482: 7)
        - Chapter 17 (Folder 482: 8)
        - Chapter 18 (Folder 482: 9)
        - Chapter 19 (Folder 482: 10)
        - Chapter 20 (Folder 482: 11)
        - Appendix and bibliography (Folder 482: 12)
      - Bound galley. Introduction and chapters 1-5 only (Folder 483: 1)
  - "On the Status and the Methods of Science,"., 1963 (Folder 483: 2)
    Radio broadcast, British Broadcasting Corporation, London, England. Typescript
  - "Models, Instruments, and Truth: The Rationality Principle in the Sciences,"., 1963 February 26
    Speech, Department of Economics, Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachussets.
    - Typescript (Folder 483: 3)
    - Revised version, "Models, Instruments, and Truth: The Status of the Rationality Principle in the Social Sciences,", 1974?
      - Typescript (Folder 483: 4)
      - Proofs (Folder 483: 5)
  - "Science: Problems, Aims, Responsibilities,"., 1963 April 17 (Folder 483: 6)
    Speech, Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology, Atlantic City, New Jersey. Typescript
  - "The Open Society and the Democratic State,"., 1963 August (Folder 483: 7)
    Speech, Indian Institute of Public Administration, Delhi, India. Typescript
  - "Of Clouds and Clocks: An Approach to the Problem of Rationality and the Freedom of Man,"., 1965 April 21 (Folder 483: 8)
    The Arthur Holly Compton Memorial Lecture, Washington University, St. Louis, Missouri. Typescript draft edited for inclusion in Paul E. Meehl Festschrift, Selected Philosophical and Methodological Papers, 1991
  - "A Note on the Difference between the Lorentz-Fitzgerald Contraction and the Einstein Contraction," The British Journal for the Philosophy of Science,., 1966 February (Folder 483: 9)
  - "A Revised Definition of Natural Necessity," The British Journal for the Philosophy of Science, 1968 February
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Folder 483: 10)
    - Holograph (Folder 483: 11)
    - Typescript (Folder 483: 12)
    - Proofs (Folder 484: 1)
  - "A Pluralist Approach to the Philosophy of History," in Erich Streissler, ed., Roads to Freedom: Essays in Honour of F. A. von Hayek,., 1969 (Folder 484: 2)
  - "Conversation with Karl Popper," in Modern British Philosophy, Bryan Magee, ed.,., 1971 (Folder 484: 3)
  - "Particle Annihilation and the Argument of Einstein, Podolsky, and Rosen," in Wolfgang Yourgrau and Alwyn van der Merwe, ed., Perspectives in Quantum Theory: Essays in Honour of Alfred Lande,., 1971 (Folder 484: 4)
    Proofs
  - "Logischer Positivismus und Dialektik,"., 1971 December 9 (Folder 484: 5)
    Radio broadcast, Norddeutscher Rundfunk, Hamburg, Germany. Typescript
  - Objective Knowledge: An Evolutionary Approach,., 1972 (Folder 484: 6)
    Proofs (incomplete)
  - "On Reason and the Open Society," Encounter,., 1972 (Folder 484: 7)
  - "The Myth of the Framework,"., 1973 April 11 (Folder 484: 8)
    Lecture, University of Otago, New Zealand. Typescript
  - "The Rationality of Scientific Revolutions,"., 1973 November (Folder 484: 9)
    The Herbert Spencer Lecture, Oxford, England. Correspondence and typescript
  - "The Frankfurt School,"., 1973 December (Folder 484: 10)
    Radio interview (not broadcast), British Broadcasting Corporation, London, England. Typescript
  - Unended Quest: An Intellectual Autobiography, 1976
    - First edition,., 1976
      - Chapters 1-10 (Folder 484: 11)
      - Chapters 11-20 (Folder 484: 12)
      - Chapters 21-30 (Folder 484: 13)
      - Chapters 31-40 (Folder 484: 14)
    - Fourth edition,., 1978 (Folder 485: 1)
    - Sixth edition,., 1982 (Folder 485: 2)
      Corrections
    - Seventh edition,., 1986 (Folder 485: 3)
      Typewritten preface
    - Eighth edition, 1992
      - Preface. (Folder 485: 4)
      - Postscript. (Folder 485: 5)
  - "The Death of Theories and of Ideologies,"., 1976 April 14 (Folder 485: 6)
    Speech, 2nd International Symposium on Philosophy, Sparta, Greece. Typescript.
  - "Unsere Pflicht ist, optimistich zu Zein,". Interview (unpublished), Spiegel., 1977 ca. July (Folder 485: 7)
    Typescript and proofs
  - "Natural Selection and the Emergence of the Mind,"., 1977 November 8
    Darwin lecture, Darwin College, Cambridge, England. Version for publication in Dialectica, 1978
    - Typescript (Folder 485: 8)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Folder 485: 9)
  - "Three Worlds,"., 1978 April 7
    The Tanner Lecture on Human Values, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, Michigan
    - Typescript (Folder 485: 10)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Folder 485: 11)
  - Dei beiden Grundprobleme der Erkenntnistheorie, 1979
    - New appendix, 1993
      - Holograph (Folder 485: 12)
      - Typescript (Folder 485: 13)
    - English version, "The Two Fundamental Problems of the Theory of Knowledge," edited by Troels Eggers Hansen and translated by Andreas Pickel, 1994
      - Typescript
        - Book 1
          - Table of contents and preface (Folder 485: 14)
          - Chapters 1-4 (Folder 485: 15)
          - Chapters 5-6 (Folder 486: 1)
          - Chapters 7-8 (Folder 486: 2)
          - Chapters 9-10 (Folder 486: 3)
        - Book 2
          - Chapters 1-5 (Folder 486: 4)
          - Chapters 6-10 (Folder 486: 5)
          - Appendix (Folder 486: 6)
          - Postscript by Troels Eggers Hansen (Folder 486: 7)
      - Correspondence, 1988-1994 (Folder 486: 8)
  - "Revolution in Our Idea of Knowledge,"., 1979 March 26 (Folder 487: 1)
    Speech, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, D.C. Correspondence, 1979-1980
  - "Wissen und Nichtwissen,"., 1979 June 8 (Folder 487: 2)
    See also original accession of Popper papers, box 222.
    Speech upon receiving an honorary doctorate from the Johann Wolgang Goethe-Universitat, Frankfurt am Main, Germany. Includes remarks by Gerd Fleischmann. Typescript
  - "Schopferische Selbstkritik in Wissenschaft und Kunst,"., 1979 July 26 (Folder 487: 3)
    Opening address, Salzburg Festival, Salzburg, Austria. Typescript
  - "Uber die sogenannten Quelllen der menschlichen Erkenntnis,"., 1979 July 27 (Folder 487: 4)
    Speech upon receiving an honorary doctorate from the Universitat Salzburg, Salzburg, Austria. Typescript
  - "Uber den Zusammenprall von Kulturen,"., 1980 May 14
    Speech, Austrian Expatriates Society, Vienna, Austria
    - Typescript (Folder 487: 5)
    - English version. (Folder 487: 6)
  - "Toleration and Intellectual Responsibility,"., 1981 March 13 (Folder 487: 7)
    J. B. Morell memorial address, University of York, York, England. Typescript
  - "Duldsamkeit und intellektuelle Verantworlichkeit,"., 1981 May 26 (Folder 487: 8)
    Speech upon receiving the Leopold-Lucas Prize, Tubingen, Germany. Typescript
  - "An Experiment to Interpret E.P.R. Action-at-a-Distance: The Possible Detection of Real De Broglie Waves" (with Augusto Garuccio and Jean-Pierre Vigier), Epistemological Letters,., 1981 July (Folder 487: 9)
  - "The Place of Mind in Nature,"., 1981 October 6 (Folder 487: 10)
    Speech (not delivered in person), Nobel Conference XVII, Gustavus Adolphus College, St. Peter, Minnesota. Typescript original, published in Mind in Nature, Elvee, Richard Q. (ed.), 1981, and revised draft, typescript with holograph annotations, dated 1982/1983
  - "Possible Direct Physical Detection of De Broglie Waves" (with Augusto Garuccio and Jean-Paul Vigier), Physics Letters,., 1981 December 7 (Folder 487: 11)
  - "The Importance of Critical Discussion: An Argument for Human Rights and Democracy," Free Inquiry,., 1981/1982 Winter (Folder 487: 12)
  - Postscript to The Logic of Scientific Discovery,., 1982-1983 (Folder 487: 13-14)
    Holograph (incomplete)
  - "Erkenntnis und Gestaltung der Wirklichkeit,"., 1982 August 25 (Box 488)
    Paper, The European Forum Alpbach 1982, Alpbach, Austria
    - Typescript (Folder 488: 1)
    - English version
      - Typescript (Folder 488: 2)
      - Correspondence with John Offenberger, 1986-1990 (Folder 488: 3)
  - "Bucher und Gedanken,"., 1982 November 2
    Speech, Opening of the 35th Austrian Bookweek, Vienna, Austria
    - Holograph (Folder 488: 4)
    - Version published in Anzeiger des osterreichischen Buchhandels,., 1983 January (Folder 488: 5)
    - English version. Typewritten drafts
      - 1982-1983 (Folder 488: 6)
      - 1984 (Folder 488: 7)
      - 1985 (Folder 488: 8)
  - "A Proof of the Impossibility of Inductive Probability" (with David W. Miller), Mind,., 1983 April 21 (Folder 489: 1)
  - "Realism in Quantum Mechanics and a New Version of the EPR Experiment,"., 1983 May 4 (Folder 489: 2)
    Paper, Workshop on Open Questions in Quantum Physics, Bari, Italy. Typescript
  - "Evolutionary Epistemology,"., 1983 May 7
    Public lecture, Workshop on Open Questions in Quantum Physics, Bari, Italy
    - Typescript (Folder 489: 3)
    - Revised version for publication in Evolutionary Theory: Paths into the Future,., 1994 (Folder 489: 4)
      Typescript, 1993
  - "Evolutionare Erkenntnistheorie,"., 1983 August 23 (Folder 489: 5)
    Discussion with Konrad Lorenz, The European Forum Alpbach 1983, Alpbach, Austria. Typescript
  - "The Growth of Human Knowledge and Its Influence on Our Environment,"., 1983 August 23 (Folder 489: 6)
    Lecture, The European Forum Alpbach 1983, Alpbach, Austria. Typescript
  - "Some Unfashionable Views on Quantum Mechanics,"., 1983 December 7 (Folder 489: 7)
    Speech, Imperial College, London, England. Typescript
  - "The Critical Attitude in Medicine: The Need for a New Ethics" (with Neil McIntyre), British Medical Journal,., 1983 December 24-31 (Folder 489: 8)
  - Auf der Suche nach einer besseren Welt, 1984
    - Foreword. (Folder 489: 9)
    - Proofs (Folder 489: 10)
    - Proofs (Contd.) (Folder 490: 1-2)
    - English version, In Search of a Better World, 1992
      - Preliminary draft. (Folder 490: 3-4)
      - Final draft
        - Typescript
          - Chapters 1-6 (Folder 490: 5)
          - Chapters 7-12 (Folder 490: 6)
        - Proofs (Box 491)
          - Chapters 1-6 (Folder 491: 1)
          - Chapters 7-12 (Folder 491: 2)
      - Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Folder 491: 3)
  - "Science and Some of Its Enemies,"., 1984 May 8 (Folder 491: 4)
    Lecture, Institute for Philosophical Studies, Naples, Italy. Typescript
  - "Thought and Experience, and Evolutionary Epistemology; Or, How the Lynxes Got Their Sharp Eyes,"., 1984 May 9-11 (Folder 491: 5)
    Speech, Academia Nazionale dei Lincei, Rome, Italy. Holograph, typescript, proofs, and correspondence
  - "Response Upon Receiving the Award of the Fondation Tocqueville,"., 1984 November 5
    Speech, Fondation Tocqueville, Valognes, France
    - Holograph and typescript (Folder 491: 6)
    - French translation. (Folder 491: 7)
    - Correspondence with Peter Carrington, Michel d'Ornano, and Jacques Pezier, 1984 (Folder 491: 8)
  - "The Proofs of Non-Locality: Where Lies the Mistake?" (with Thomas D. Angelidis),., 1984 November 15 (Folder 491: 9)
  - "Counterexamples to a Proof of Clauser and Horne (with Thomas D. Angelidis),., 1985 (Folder 491: 10)
  - "The Non-Existence of Probabilistic Inductive Support,"., 1985 (Folder 491: 11)
  - Popper Selections, David W. Miller, ed.,. German version, 1985 1995 (Box 492)
    - Proofs (Folder 492: 1)
    - Correspondence,., 1993-1995 (Folder 492: 2)
      Includes correspondence between David M. Miller and Georg Siebeck
  - "Towards a Local Explanatory Theory of the Einstein-Podolsky-Rosen-Bohm Experiment" (with Thomas D. Angelidis),., 1985 (Folder 492: 3)
  - Die Zukunft ist offen: Das Altenberger Gesprach, mit den Texten des Wiener Popper-Symposiums,., 1985 (Folder 492: 4)
    Postscript. Holograph and typescript
  - "Deductive Dependence" (with David W. Miller),., 1985 February (Folder 492: 5)
    Paper presented at the IVth Catalan Logic Congress, Barcelona, Spain. Typescript
  - "Why Quantum Theory Is Local?"., 1985 May 17 (Folder 492: 6)
    Lecture, International Academy for the Philosophy of Science, Universitat Fribourg, Fribourg, Switzerland. Holography and typescript
  - Lecture on evolutionary biology,., 1985 June 18 (Folder 492: 7)
    Paper delivered by David W. Miller, Geymonat Conference, Milan, Italy. Holograph and typescript
  - Speech, The European Forum Alpbach 1985, Evolution and the Future of Mankind, Alpbach, Austria,., 1985 August 23 (Folder 492: 8)
  - "Freude an der Arbeit,"., 1985 September 12 (Folder 492: 9)
    Speech, Symposium - Denken uber die Zukunft, Zurich, Switzerland. Holograph and correspondence
  - "Erkenntnistheorie und das Problem des Friedens,"., 1985 September 19
    Speech
    - Holograph (Folder 492: 10)
    - Typescript (Folder 492: 11)